This material is made available to you by or on
NOTE CONF
behalf of the University of Melbourne under section 113P of
the Copyright Act 1968.
NOTE CONF
It may be subject to copyright.
For more information, visit the university copyright website.
NOTE CONF
Good morning.
This week we're going to talk about information security policy.
NOTE CONF
Um, As you can see, we are going week to
week in this part of the, the subject, um, going
NOTE CONF
cycling through the various managerial controls.
We've covered risk last week and this week we're covering
NOTE CONF
policy.
We're going to be covering strategy and then security education,
NOTE CONF
training and awareness before we then move to more advanced
topics, um, later in the semester.
NOTE CONF
So This, today's learning objectives or this week's learning objectives
are, uh, define what is information security policy.
NOTE CONF
So what is an information security policy?
Why do organizations have one?
NOTE CONF
What are the motivations for that?
Uh, what are the differences between an effective and ineffective
NOTE CONF
policy, and identify ways in which policy effectiveness can be
improved.
NOTE CONF
In the background to a lot of these learning objectives
is a deeper understanding of what kind of um artifact
NOTE CONF
the policy is and why it is so challenging to
Have a good policy in place.
NOTE CONF
Like everything, we start from the triplet model.
We've talked about risk scenarios last week, and specifically, we
NOTE CONF
talked about um how when you have a range of
scenarios, well, how you go about identifying them, but then
NOTE CONF
how you estimate the likelihood and impact of scenarios so
that you can sort them in terms of criticality, and
NOTE CONF
then what are the approaches that you have at your
disposal to try to address those risk scenarios and the
NOTE CONF
whole The story around the triplet model and the definition
of security in the subject is that your entire purpose
NOTE CONF
is to understand what you're protecting, what you're protecting those
assets from, and what are the scenarios within which those,
NOTE CONF
you know, those risks can emerge, and then how to
control those scenarios so you can have some level of
NOTE CONF
security, and that is what the management of security is
fundamentally about.
NOTE CONF
It's about knowing that security is always a balance.
There's no such thing as perfect security.
NOTE CONF
You can never reduce your risk to zero.
You don't have unlimited funds, and you have to find
NOTE CONF
that balance between the risk that you are exposed to
and the extent to which you can control them, given
NOTE CONF
the resources that you have.
And so this week, last week, we talked about risk
NOTE CONF
management as a form of formal control.
It's sort of got an outsized influence because we define
NOTE CONF
security as a risk management problem.
So if it's at it at its heart, it is
NOTE CONF
a risk management problem, then this is a very powerful
control.
NOTE CONF
Uh, but this week we're talking about another managerial control,
which is security policy.
NOTE CONF
What is an information security policy?
Well, I mean, we always default to the bigger question,
NOTE CONF
which is what is policy?
Uh, policy is a plan or course of action that
NOTE CONF
conveys instructions from an organization's senior management to those who
make decisions, take actions, um, and perform other duties.
NOTE CONF
There's a lot of definitions of policy out there.
There are no good definitions of policy, to be honest,
NOTE CONF
but essentially policy is about intent and will.
When the leadership of an organization wants to declare its
NOTE CONF
intention around something and direct its employees to do something,
it comes up with a policy.
NOTE CONF
Um, and so, on the left-hand side, we have the
textbook definition of policy from the textbook that you're studying.
NOTE CONF
And on the right hand side is in a very
old 1985, 1995, sorry, definition that provides a little bit
NOTE CONF
more detail for those who crave detail.
The set of laws, rules and practices that regulate how
NOTE CONF
an organization manages, protects, and distributes resources to achieve specified
security policy objectives.
NOTE CONF
So it declares a policy to be a set of
laws, rules and practices.
NOTE CONF
So if you want to know what is it.
In a concrete sense.
NOTE CONF
The, uh, this definition says that it is a set
of laws, regulations, rules and practices.
NOTE CONF
And what is it, what do they do?
They regulate how you manage, protect, and distribute resources.
NOTE CONF
Why?
Because you want to, you want to achieve particular policy
NOTE CONF
objectives.
And these laws, rules and practices must identify criteria for
NOTE CONF
according individuals authority, for giving individuals authority and may specify
conditions under which individuals are permitted to exercise their authority.
NOTE CONF
So in the second, the second half of that definition,
the authors suggest that further than just the laws, rules
NOTE CONF
and practices, it's actually the fact that they identify criteria
for individuals exercising their authority and the circumstances within which
NOTE CONF
they can exercise that authority.
And we know this might seem very abstract and very
NOTE CONF
wishy-washy, but if you think about it from a leadership
point of view.
NOTE CONF
There are, there are 3 key players in an organization.
There's the board of directors, and there is the CEO
NOTE CONF
and then the C-suite executive as an extension of them,
and then the rest of the organization.
NOTE CONF
And if you want to understand the rules, I think
I said this before, I'll sort of say it again.
NOTE CONF
The board of directors is, the analogy is like a,
uh, like a soccer team or like a sports team.
NOTE CONF
You've got a sports team, you've got a coach, and
you've got the owner of the team.
NOTE CONF
The owner of the team is the board of directors,
similar to the board of directors.
NOTE CONF
The coach is the CEO and the team that's playing
on the ground, they are the actual organization.
NOTE CONF
So, this is a really interesting analogy and a useful
one because the owner of the, of the team may
NOTE CONF
not know how to play soccer at all, right?
Their entire job is to appoint the coach.
NOTE CONF
They don't meddle with who's playing on the ground because
this is not their game, right?
NOTE CONF
They don't understand soccer or whatever sport that they own
or basketball or whatever.
NOTE CONF
So their job as a board of directors is to
appoint the coach.
NOTE CONF
That's what the board of directors do.
They appoint the CEO.
NOTE CONF
If the board of directors doesn't like what the CEO
is doing or where the organization is going, they fire
NOTE CONF
the CEO and hire a new one.
But that is really their only point of control.
NOTE CONF
You fire the CEO and hire a new one.
This is how you change the direction of the organization.
NOTE CONF
You don't start meddling with the internals of the organization,
just like the owner of a soccer team doesn't go
NOTE CONF
onto the pitch and start playing soccer, or say, I
don't like this player, hire and get me a different
NOTE CONF
player.
This is not your role.
NOTE CONF
Your job is to have the coach.
So how do the board of directors then influence the
NOTE CONF
organization outside of hiring that CEO, or how does the
CEO signal to the board of directors?
NOTE CONF
That he or she is serious about running the organization
and frequently it's through policy.
NOTE CONF
It's through setting the rules, setting the laws, setting the
practices.
NOTE CONF
Laws is a bit more government level, but setting the
rules and practices, this is how you tell.
NOTE CONF
This is how the CEO tells the board that I'm
serious about how I run the organization.
NOTE CONF
A security policy is something that a CEO will put
in place as a signal to the board that I
NOTE CONF
am a very serious player here or a coach-chair, and
I'm going to run this organization well.
NOTE CONF
Right, that's, you know, really within the CEO's remit is
setting these policies as a way to protect himself or
NOTE CONF
herself from the board, right?
There's a whole power thingy play going on between the
NOTE CONF
board and the CEO always.
There's a lot of tension between those two characters, mainly
NOTE CONF
because the board is always using audit as a way
to second guess what the CEO is telling them about
NOTE CONF
what's going on on the ground, right?
It's just like a, a Sports owner, basically, you know,
NOTE CONF
not happy with the coach.
They've just lost the, you know, a major cup, FA
NOTE CONF
Cup, Premier League, whatever, and you don't, you don't, your,
your team's not playing well, and you wanna find some
NOTE CONF
way to, you know, ask the coach why this is
happening.
NOTE CONF
And this, this is a tension between the board of
directors and the CEO always.
NOTE CONF
And Part of that in that play here is the
role that the policy is playing in trying to assure
NOTE CONF
both sides that things are under control.
So why do we have policies?
NOTE CONF
There's so many reasons why, and I think most employees
think that the main reason why you have a policy
NOTE CONF
is so that you can, the organization can set rules
about what, what's allowed and what's not allowed.
NOTE CONF
But this is, I think, I think that's part of
the story, but this is for me not the main
NOTE CONF
reason.
The main reason is actually marketing, right?
NOTE CONF
It's actually a signal from the organization to say, hey,
we take this seriously.
NOTE CONF
So you can imagine.
In a security context, if an employee violates an organization's
NOTE CONF
a rule, right, in an organization and the organization wants
to fire the employee and the employee takes the organization
NOTE CONF
to court, the first thing the judge is gonna ask
is what directives did you give employees about that action,
NOTE CONF
which means, do you have a policy on this action?
And if the owner says, I fired this person, sorry,
NOTE CONF
the CEO says, I fired this person, but um there's
no policy, the judge is gonna say, you can't fire
NOTE CONF
a person if you don't have a policy.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So not having a policy is unforgivable.
Having a bad policy is forgivable, right?
NOTE CONF
You can fix the policy, say, oh, that statement, it's
not an accurate statement, or there's a better statement, yeah,
NOTE CONF
fine, fix it.
But not having a policy comes down to due diligence,
NOTE CONF
something that the board and the CEO will be held
accountable for, right?
NOTE CONF
So having a policy is really critical.
So it's a signal.
NOTE CONF
You demonstrate commitment to the board.
And to the external environment that the organization takes something
NOTE CONF
seriously.
Because you want to clarify the obligations of the organization,
NOTE CONF
you want to say, I take this seriously.
I'm going to do the following things about this problem.
NOTE CONF
We're going to have a look at the ANZ Bank's
security policy in a moment, and you'll see how they
NOTE CONF
do that on their main ISMS page.
Number 2, to set direction for security.
NOTE CONF
Security is critical.
You need to tell people that it's critical and what
NOTE CONF
it means and why it's critical and how it's critical
and what to do about it, right?
NOTE CONF
To specify and clarify what the organization is responsible for.
What are we responsible for as the C-suite executive or
NOTE CONF
the leadership of the organization?
What is our responsibility?
NOTE CONF
What is the responsibility of our employees?
There's a distinction between the two, and that's made clear
NOTE CONF
in the policy.
To influence spending on security, what's important to us.
NOTE CONF
If it's important to us, we're going to spend on
it, right?
NOTE CONF
As an auditor, one of the first things I used
to look at when somebody would say, hey, we take
NOTE CONF
security very seriously, is you go straight to the budget
and see how much money have they allocated for security.
NOTE CONF
And if they haven't allocated any money for security, they're
not serious about security, right?
NOTE CONF
So, you don't look at what they're saying, you look,
you don't look at what their lips are saying, you
NOTE CONF
look at what their hands are doing, right?
They can say whatever they want about how important security
NOTE CONF
is and they usually come out and say that when
there's a major incident, right?
NOTE CONF
But you want to tell whether the organization is serious
or not, look at their budget.
NOTE CONF
Look at how much they're spending, and if their security
budget is coming from a capital expenditure budget, like there's
NOTE CONF
one IT budget and all security is coming for it,
it means that there's no dedicated security money, which means
NOTE CONF
security people have to beg the IT people for money,
which means they're not serious about security.
NOTE CONF
Serious organizations have a dedicated, allocated budget that is available
every year for security and will be spent on security.
NOTE CONF
And you don't have to fight for it, you don't
have to beg for it.
NOTE CONF
It's there for you, right?
That's a very strong signal that the organization takes security
NOTE CONF
very seriously.
And to provide continuity in management, right?
NOTE CONF
So, if I'm a new CEO or I'm a new
CISO and I don't know what the organization stands for,
NOTE CONF
I should be able to go to the policy and
be able to tell, right?
NOTE CONF
That's continuity.
If you fire the CISO and a new CISO comes
NOTE CONF
in, the policy should tell them a lot about how
the organization treats security.
NOTE CONF
So there's continuity.
There are other reasons To formalize grounds for termination, you
NOTE CONF
want to fire an employee for violating security, you first
have to tell them what is the rule and what
NOTE CONF
they're not supposed to violate, and what are the consequences
of those actions if they violate.
NOTE CONF
Um, to create employee awareness, to tell them the security
is important, but more than just hey, security is important
NOTE CONF
to give them detailed information.
About how to behave, about what software they can download,
NOTE CONF
about whether they can use the internet for personal, you
know, banking or whatever during work hours, uh, what kind
NOTE CONF
of information they can store and where if it's personal
information, can they take employee, can they take work organizational
NOTE CONF
work product and actually store it on a personal machine?
What can they do with their mobile phone?
NOTE CONF
What they cannot do with their mobile phone?
What about a work phone, etc.
NOTE CONF
all those sorts of things.
Um, to provide mechanism for stating what behavior is acceptable.
NOTE CONF
And so you have acceptable use behavior policies or, or,
or, you know, practices, guidelines that are issued to employees.
NOTE CONF
This is how you can use your work computer.
This is how, you know, this is what you're allowed
NOTE CONF
to do, what you're not allowed to do, etc.
etc.
NOTE CONF
What are the ramifications of nonconformance with the policy, and
to encourage appropriate conduct.
NOTE CONF
Right What is good behavior and encouraging that?
Organizations, especially small to medium sized organizations, frequently don't have
NOTE CONF
a security policy until they try to go for accreditation
on some kind of international standard like an ISO standard,
NOTE CONF
in which case they must have a policy to qualify
or to be accredited, and that's when they start thinking
NOTE CONF
about writing a policy.
Policy is the least expensive.
NOTE CONF
Control to no, it's the least expensive means of control
in the sense that it costs you the least in
NOTE CONF
writing a document.
It's cheap to get somebody to write a document, and
NOTE CONF
most organizations copy and paste from somebody else's policy anyway.
But it is the hardest to get right.
NOTE CONF
Very, very difficult to get a good policy in place,
mainly because organizations write policy without understanding.
NOTE CONF
The environment within which the policy will be operationalized.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So if you don't understand your organization, and you create
a policy about what is right and what is wrong,
NOTE CONF
what is acceptable, what is not acceptable, what do you
think is going to happen?
NOTE CONF
Open question.
What do you think is gonna happen?
NOTE CONF
It's not Policy is not implemented.
Sorry, it will not be effective.
NOTE CONF
But you see, there's an interesting thing here.
There's, there's two policies in play in every organization.
NOTE CONF
There is the formal policy, which is the policy that
the organization has written, put in the document, and either
NOTE CONF
put on the internet or on your shelf somewhere, yeah.
And then there's the informal policy, the unofficial policy, which
NOTE CONF
is the behavior that is acceptable in the organization.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So we say, the behavior that is tolerated is the
policy, not what's written on the document.
NOTE CONF
So if the document says do not put your passwords
on a yellow sticky and put it on your machine,
NOTE CONF
but everybody's got a yellow sticky on the machine with
their password, what do you think the policy of the
NOTE CONF
organization is?
Is it do not have yellow stickies on your computer
NOTE CONF
with a password, or is it you are allowed to
have yellow stickies with the password on your computer?
NOTE CONF
Which one do you think it is?
Of course it's a culture problem, but what's, that's a
NOTE CONF
different, uh, completely different issue.
Culture problem.
NOTE CONF
Let's fix the culture problem.
But what's the policy in the organization?
NOTE CONF
The policy is you are allowed to have passwords on
stickies, right?
NOTE CONF
Although the organization says you are not allowed to, you
are allowed to, because everybody's doing it.
NOTE CONF
So, if you go to court and the judge says
to the, to an individual who was fired for having
NOTE CONF
a yellow sticky on their, you know, on their computer
with their password on it.
NOTE CONF
Is this common practice, and they said yes, and my
supervisors do it as well.
NOTE CONF
You cannot fire this individual.
It doesn't matter what the policy says.
NOTE CONF
It doesn't matter what the document says.
It is accepted cultural practice in the organization to have
NOTE CONF
your password on a yellow sticky on a computer, so
you cannot fire somebody for doing something that everybody else
NOTE CONF
has accepted as common and routine.
So what's the policy?
NOTE CONF
The policy is accepted practice, always over what's in a
document.
NOTE CONF
The, the company, of course, is going to argue till
they're blue in the face that the policy is what
NOTE CONF
in the document, you know, do as I tell you,
not as I do, right?
NOTE CONF
But we understand that is not the case.
And certainly in the legal, in a legal pro you
NOTE CONF
know, case, um, the judge is going to consider not
just what the company has issued in the document, but
NOTE CONF
what the practice is.
So some basic rules, your policy should never conflict with
NOTE CONF
law.
Never ever tell your employees to do something that's illegal.
NOTE CONF
You might think it's obvious.
No, it's not, because legal jurisdictions vary so much from
NOTE CONF
state to state, from country to country, a multinational corporation
is going to struggle with laws.
NOTE CONF
Really, really struggle because most multinational corporations have so many
jurisdictions that they operate in they can't keep track of
NOTE CONF
the laws and the rules in each state and each
territory and so they may be in violation of a
NOTE CONF
whole range of different.
Laws across the world.
NOTE CONF
In fact, there might be contradictions, you know, if you,
if you conform with one law's expectations, you are directly
NOTE CONF
in violation with another because those two laws compete with
each other.
NOTE CONF
So how to reconcile that, that's part of the problem
of having good policy.
NOTE CONF
So never conflict with law harder than it looks.
It should always stand up in court.
NOTE CONF
The policy in many companies is considered to be a
legal document, and the company, when they sign off on
NOTE CONF
that policy, they're held accountable against their own policy.
So if they violate, if the leadership violates the policy,
NOTE CONF
they're in trouble because it's a legal document.
It's a contract.
NOTE CONF
Or they behave around the policy like it's a contract,
right?
NOTE CONF
So you could um be in violation of your own
contract, and you could be in a lot of trouble
NOTE CONF
for that, which is why the wording of policy is
so critical that most big banks, for instance, get lawyers
NOTE CONF
to write the policy, right?
Because lawyers will be gaming all the scenarios where the
NOTE CONF
organization's going to get caught up in its own words.
That's why they're very careful around the wording of how
NOTE CONF
they write their policy, and that's why in a way
policy is so often ineffective, because it's written for lawyers
NOTE CONF
by lawyers, for judges, or for contract disputes, etc.
and the average employee doesn't understand it.
NOTE CONF
So that one policy document is doing so many different
things that it's very difficult to write a policy document
NOTE CONF
that's actually understandable and meaningful and practical and usable and
implementable while standing in court and meeting all the court's
NOTE CONF
rules and laws and weight of evidence and all that
other stuff, right?
NOTE CONF
So that one document trying to do so many things,
this is a big problem.
NOTE CONF
OK, properly supported and administered, which means that if there
are changes, which means you need to resource the policy.
NOTE CONF
It's not just I wrote it once and I never
have to look at it again.
NOTE CONF
The policy changes with the organization.
The organization changes, the policy changes.
NOTE CONF
And so if it's not resourced, then the organization then
outruns the policy and the policy becomes a historical artifact
NOTE CONF
that's outdated and nobody pays attention to.
Well, they were never paying attention to it anyway.
NOTE CONF
Now there are more reasons to not pay attention to
it.
NOTE CONF
It should contribute to the success of the organization, and
it will if it's a good, if it's a good
NOTE CONF
policy, right?
Because a lot of the problems that you couldn't solve
NOTE CONF
by training people, you could solve if the policy was
immediately understandable, right?
NOTE CONF
If somebody rings up your administrative assistant and says, hey,
send me 10 number of dollars, and the assistant has
NOTE CONF
read the policy, and they know that you're not allowed
to do that, they're going to say, I'm not allowed
NOTE CONF
to do that, right?
And that saves you a ton of money in training.
NOTE CONF
And software controls and blah blah, when somebody has said,
I read the policy, the policy is you can't do
NOTE CONF
that.
Very effective and it should involve end users of information
NOTE CONF
systems.
If you're writing a security policy and you don't know
NOTE CONF
anything about the people that are supposed to be using
that policy.
NOTE CONF
Um, to be able to do their work, then your
policy is not going to work, right?
NOTE CONF
It's ineffective, it's, it's, it's disengaged, and out of, out
of contact with the end users.
NOTE CONF
So Along with the policy conversation is the change management
conversation, which is if we are doing a wholesale change
NOTE CONF
or a significant major structural change inside the organization, um,
what order do we do changes in?
NOTE CONF
And the bull's-eye model, which is straight from the textbook,
suggests, um, this is not my research, this is the,
NOTE CONF
the the person who wrote the textbook says that you
should start with policy and make changes to policy before
NOTE CONF
you start working on networks.
Well, before you start working on the next thing, which
NOTE CONF
is networks, and then systems and then applications.
So when you do change management, you start, they're suggesting
NOTE CONF
you start with policy.
And then you work your way to applications.
NOTE CONF
You don't make changes in applications and then work your
way to policies.
NOTE CONF
And I mean, I can understand, I'm sure you can
appreciate that there's good reason for that.
NOTE CONF
If the organization hasn't yet decided what the change means
for the organization, and they start making changes to applications
NOTE CONF
and systems, and then start working inside out, you're gonna
have a problem.
NOTE CONF
You won't discover that there's a conflict between this change
and other things that are going on in the organization.
NOTE CONF
Until you've already implemented it.
Whereas what you should do is first of all, figure
NOTE CONF
out, I want to make a big change to the
organization.
NOTE CONF
How does that sit with where we are as an
organization and all the other things that are going on.
NOTE CONF
If it makes sense, then let's start implementing.
Right, so that starts at a policy level and then
NOTE CONF
it moves down to the various technological layers outside in
network systems, applications, right, all the way to the end
NOTE CONF
user interface, right?
The end user interfaces with the organization's IT through applications,
NOTE CONF
not through systems and networks directly, so it kind of
makes sense to go that way.
NOTE CONF
The word policy is a It's a very overarching term
that involves a lot of different levels of documents.
NOTE CONF
So, a strategic level policy, an operational level policy, a
tactical level policy, there are different words for it, right?
NOTE CONF
But here we have managerial policy, operational, acceptable use, strategic,
all these different types of policies, they're all just trying
NOTE CONF
to give guidance.
from security mission to firewall policy, which is what is
NOTE CONF
what is the configuration of my firewall to uh internet
usage policy, what are people able to use their internet
NOTE CONF
for or not?
Email policy, what can you, you know, uh, what kind
NOTE CONF
of words or what kind of documents should not leave
the organization, which should patch into your data leak prevention
NOTE CONF
protocols.
And um how does your security program support the business
NOTE CONF
at a strategic level?
How is it aligned to it?
NOTE CONF
How does it achieve business objectives at a very strategic
level?
NOTE CONF
And so we have these different terms.
Policies usually, the term policy is reserved for strategic level
NOTE CONF
documents.
And then you have this word called standards.
NOTE CONF
And I was having a bit of a debate with
Mazzino last night at the tutors meeting.
NOTE CONF
The word standards.
When people use the word standard, they usually think ISO
NOTE CONF
standard, international standard or industry standard.
But in the US in the book that you're, you
NOTE CONF
know, prescribed textbook is an American textbook, the term standard
is actually used for an internal policy.
NOTE CONF
Right, it's a policy document made by the organization for
itself that sits under the strategic level policy.
NOTE CONF
It's called the standard.
So it's really important to, to make sure you understand
NOTE CONF
the difference between the two.
In this subject, generally, when we use the word standards,
NOTE CONF
we mean ISO standard, right?
But it's just for you to know that there are
NOTE CONF
different levels of policies.
So you've got Senior levels or strategic level policies, you've
NOTE CONF
got middle management or, you know, tactical level policies, you've
got practices, guidelines and procedures, and they're just vary in
NOTE CONF
the level of detail that they provide.
So more detail as you go down, more specific to
NOTE CONF
the context as you go down, and more general and
abstract as you go up.
NOTE CONF
For policies to be effective, first of all, you have
to be able to disseminate, you have to disseminate them
NOTE CONF
to the people who need them, right?
And it's not, most people think that means write a
NOTE CONF
policy, email it to everybody in the organization, or set
up an intranet, which is called the policy domain and
NOTE CONF
and give them the address so people can go and
look up the policy.
NOTE CONF
Uh, no, right?
That's the 1980s, 19990s view of what policy is like.
NOTE CONF
Now, we've been arguing for now more than two decades
that policy only makes sense if it pops up at
NOTE CONF
the point where you're about to make a decision, right?
If you're about to do something, and the organization has
NOTE CONF
a policy directive on it, a pop-up should come up
on your, on your screen that says, did you know
NOTE CONF
that the organization's directive on this particular decision you're about
to make is blah.
NOTE CONF
So now you don't have to go and look for
the 1000 page, you know, book and flick through it
NOTE CONF
and find where in the organization's directives is the part
that relates to the decision you're about to make.
NOTE CONF
Right, that makes no sense at all.
And that's the way most organizations have been operating for
NOTE CONF
generations, right?
Write a policy, put it on a shelf.
NOTE CONF
It's your job to know what it is, right?
It's not practical, but it's your job, right?
NOTE CONF
So now, I think the expectation is a bit more
that you can, that the organization should find a way
NOTE CONF
to inform the individual decision makers of what the policy
is at the point of the decision, right.
NOTE CONF
For example, using, uh, you know, pop-up box or whatever.
So, how would you disseminate a policy in an organization
NOTE CONF
so many different ways, but policy needs to be disseminated
as a document.
NOTE CONF
As maybe in emails, as training, so your training needs
to back up your policy, whatever is in your policy
NOTE CONF
should be consistent with your training, and it should pop
up at decision points.
NOTE CONF
OK?
And you might even have champions who are policy experts,
NOTE CONF
uh, who know everything about the policy.
So if you're ever We're all wondering what should I
NOTE CONF
do in this situation, you just ask, you know, a
buddy or a champion in your team who's designated the
NOTE CONF
policy expert, and you go and ask them.
So that way, the problem isn't.
NOTE CONF
Do I need to train everybody in the organization to
know everything about the policy?
NOTE CONF
It's how many champions do I need in an organization
so that people will refer to them, and that way,
NOTE CONF
policy will be followed.
Your policy needs to be understood by your target audience.
NOTE CONF
And which is another problem, right?
Because in an organization that has baby boomers, Gen Xers,
NOTE CONF
Gen Y, Gen Z, Gen Z, whatever, all the different
generations, they all take direction differently.
NOTE CONF
For a baby boomer, you just say, this is the
organization's policy, and they're not going to ask questions.
NOTE CONF
They're just going to do it.
But if you ask a Gen Z person, This is
NOTE CONF
the policy they're going to say, why?
Why should I follow?
NOTE CONF
Who, why do I care what the organization thinks?
You need to justify it to me, it needs to
NOTE CONF
make sense to me, or I'm not going to follow
it, right?
NOTE CONF
So, you have a generational gap in the way people
follow direction.
NOTE CONF
So if you write a policy for a baby boomer,
it's not going to work for a Gen Z.
NOTE CONF
You see, the same document has now got to deal
with different generations.
NOTE CONF
And then also you have different attitudes from different ethnic
groups.
NOTE CONF
So for instance, trust in government, we ran this study
some years ago, where we asked Singaporean citizens to give
NOTE CONF
um their private information to a government website and we
compare that to, I think it was Malaysians or something
NOTE CONF
else and we, or Australians, was it?
Um and completely different attitude, right?
NOTE CONF
Some citizens of some countries completely do not trust the
government and would never give any private information out, especially
NOTE CONF
the government, right?
And there's others, particularly Singaporean citizens who completely trust the
NOTE CONF
government and are very happy to give all their personal
information to the government.
NOTE CONF
And I thought that was remarkable, right, that there was
such a disparity between citizens of different countries based on
NOTE CONF
their experiences and their attitudes towards government, and we can
replace government with authority here and make the same claim
NOTE CONF
here.
In an organization, you're going to have people who have
NOTE CONF
different attitudes towards authority.
Some will follow authority.
NOTE CONF
Unquestioningly, and some will actually react very negatively to authority
and actually be put on a war footing, right?
NOTE CONF
They will become very skeptical.
Uh, they will ask lots of questions, they will be,
NOTE CONF
you know, they won't trust authority.
So, policy has to deal with all of these problems
NOTE CONF
because all of these problems exist in your audience.
And policy must be uniformly enforced.
NOTE CONF
On your audience.
So if it's selective, or there's a perception that policy
NOTE CONF
is being selective, then what's gonna happen?
People are gonna say, why are you, why are you
NOTE CONF
focusing on me, right?
You should be asking so and so person, right?
NOTE CONF
So all of these play a role.
So typical policy document structure is you have some strategic
NOTE CONF
level policies and some operational policies, and they all exist
in a big policy suite.
NOTE CONF
I'm going to, um, very quickly, how much time do
I have, I have a little bit of time to
NOTE CONF
go through this.
I want to show you ANZ's um, this is available
NOTE CONF
on your, uh, your LMS, the This is around 200,
I don't know, 5, 2008.
NOTE CONF
This is the official ANZ banking information security policy, which,
by the way, it was very hard to get hold
NOTE CONF
of because banks in particular, are very, very, you know,
they treat their, their enterprise-wide security policy as confidential.
NOTE CONF
So the CISO was very kind to allow for students
of the subject to be able to use this policy.
NOTE CONF
OK, let me just I want to read this out
to you because it's remarkable how close the language is
NOTE CONF
to what you're studying in this subject, right?
And this is all signaling from the bank to all
NOTE CONF
the stakeholders that are in their environment.
So, Information Security management systems, there's like a whole suite
NOTE CONF
of policies on the right hand side, you have access
to all of them.
NOTE CONF
So, so we rely on computer systems and the information
they contain.
NOTE CONF
Right, sounds like an unremarkable line, right?
Those are their assets.
NOTE CONF
The first line, very deliberately, is what are our assets,
right?
NOTE CONF
We rely on computer systems, they used to call them
computer systems around that time, and information.
NOTE CONF
So they've got two types of assets, digital platforms, information.
They, they don't have capability, not that they don't have
NOTE CONF
the capability, but they don't have, they don't treat their
capability as an asset because they're not an IP centric
NOTE CONF
firm, they're a bank, OK.
The information we hold and collect will advance our strategy
NOTE CONF
as effective market leaders.
This is the alignment between security and business, right?
NOTE CONF
Number 3, we need to protect this information from disclosure,
corruption and loss.
NOTE CONF
Disclosure, confidentiality, corruption, integrity, loss availability.
See how they're mapping directly on what we're talking about.
NOTE CONF
This is the triplet model in action, right?
Information security management can be likened to a security fence
NOTE CONF
around our information.
Compliance Right, so this is a compliance statement.
NOTE CONF
This is them saying we see security as a compliance
problem, right?
NOTE CONF
It's a 3 ft fence around our Our property.
However, the fence is only as strong as its weakest
NOTE CONF
link, right?
So this is a signal to all the All the
NOTE CONF
parties involved in security, if you let us down, you
can break the whole link down.
NOTE CONF
Next paragraph.
Therefore, in order to sustain this fence and the corresponding
NOTE CONF
links, a group called Global Information Security was formed.
This is them saying now that we've just in broad
NOTE CONF
strokes defined our posture on security, we have now created
a group that is responsible for security.
NOTE CONF
So this is This is them saying we are resourcing
security, not just we're talking, but we have created a
NOTE CONF
group, which means we have hired people, which means we
have dedicated budget.
NOTE CONF
We've spent money on it, and now there's somebody's responsible
within.
NOTE CONF
So we are holding some team or some group of
people responsible for security because if we didn't do that,
NOTE CONF
it means that everybody is responsible and where everybody is
responsible, nobody is responsible.
NOTE CONF
So now we've got a team that's responsible.
So, Their primary objective is to ensure that we are
NOTE CONF
all fully aware of our responsibilities with regard to maintaining
this fence and the links that encompass it.
NOTE CONF
So they're saying the prime directive of the global information
security team is to inform the rest of the organization.
NOTE CONF
Of the importance of security.
Further, it is imperative that we understand the importance of
NOTE CONF
individual accountability in order for us to effectively maintain the
strength of the fence.
NOTE CONF
So they're saying there are two groups of people that
are responsible for security in this company.
NOTE CONF
There is GIS and there's everybody.
So they've already identified the two key groups within the
NOTE CONF
opening page of the policy.
This is the structure of the way they handle security.
NOTE CONF
The purpose of our policies is to protect all information
assets from the threats they are exposed to.
NOTE CONF
That is your, uh, that's your triplet model's primary definition
of security, assets and threats, irrespective of whether the threats
NOTE CONF
are inside or outside our protective fence.
And so they're clarifying that when we say threats, we
NOTE CONF
don't just mean external, we mean internal as well.
That's a result of running an organization, where there's a
NOTE CONF
boundary between what's going on in the outside world and
the inside world, right?
NOTE CONF
Or whether they are deliberate or accidental.
So they're defining security.
NOTE CONF
They're scoping security to say it's not just purposive malicious
incidents, it's accidental ones as well, blurring the line between
NOTE CONF
safety and security.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So accidents.
And attacks, both count as security within the jurisdiction of
NOTE CONF
this particular policy, and by extension, the whole security program.
So in this one page, you get a very clear
NOTE CONF
idea of what the organization's posture is, how they define
security, who is responsible for security, what encompasses security, what's
NOTE CONF
outside of security, what are the directives of security, all
of that big picture painting is what they're doing on
NOTE CONF
the very first page, right?
So each line is very carefully crafted.
NOTE CONF
Because that opening part of the policy is going to
have a huge impact in a court case, right?
NOTE CONF
Or in any case, where they are.
Um, going to be called in.
NOTE CONF
OK, what happened there?
Sorry.
NOTE CONF
I can shut that down now, and To the back
end of this.
NOTE CONF
Oops, how am I doing this?
Yeah.
NOTE CONF
How many of you are taking a subject with Sean?
Yeah, IT strategy governance.
NOTE CONF
Yes, that's the subject you're doing with him.
I think you are.
NOTE CONF
This is, this is his PhD, um.
He did his PhD on information security policy quality, which
NOTE CONF
was to identify all the different dimensions of quality that
a policy could have in the context of security.
NOTE CONF
Right.
So, um, here are some really interesting things that you
NOTE CONF
probably never thought about when you thought of when you
start thinking about security policy.
NOTE CONF
Number one, security policy needs to be complete.
Right, which is the extent to which it addresses all
NOTE CONF
your security requirements.
So it's not just risk scenarios, but every requirement you
NOTE CONF
have in security needs to be addressed in the policy.
So the policy's completeness is at the extent to which
NOTE CONF
it addresses all the organization's security requirements.
Number 2, suitability.
NOTE CONF
Information security policy should be appropriate for the organization, so.
Different organizations that that exist in different circumstances will have
NOTE CONF
different policies.
A highly regulated sector like banking will not look anything
NOTE CONF
like an unregulated sector like, I don't know, food or,
you know, water.
NOTE CONF
So very different policies, the heavily regulated sector organizations will
have policies that are very legal, and the others may
NOTE CONF
not be as legal.
Accuracy, the extent to which security policy statements correctly address
NOTE CONF
security requirements.
Do you have security requirements.
NOTE CONF
Does the policy statements that are in the policy addressing
those requirements, do they work or not?
NOTE CONF
How accurate are they?
Interoperability, does the policy actually interact with other policies, or
NOTE CONF
does it exist in a vacuum?
Security, are you saying something in your policy that is
NOTE CONF
so sensitive that somebody who reads your policy will be
able to figure it out?
NOTE CONF
Right, and then, and then actually attacked the company.
So you might not think of the policy, security policy
NOTE CONF
as being needed as needing its own security, but it
does.
NOTE CONF
So sometimes if you put too much in your policy,
you're giving up, you know, you're, you're, you're presenting secrets
NOTE CONF
to an external party who will read your policy and
use it against you.
NOTE CONF
Analyzability, the extent to which information security policy can be
methodically examined for deficiencies.
NOTE CONF
And so I have a, a story about this many,
many years ago, um, I was working for a consulting
NOTE CONF
firm and my client was Verisign Corporation, right?
And Verisign Corporation here in Australia was about to go
NOTE CONF
through this, this compliance, um, They were applying for something
called gatekeeper compliance.
NOTE CONF
The gatekeeper is about digital certificates, and as part of
the compliance protocol they needed to assure the Australian government
NOTE CONF
that their digital certificates were actually stored in a location
that was compliant with all the security measures that the
NOTE CONF
gatekeeper protocol said needed to be in place.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So, and it, it extended to the height of the
fences and the buildings that held the digital certificates, um,
NOTE CONF
and the, the size of the bolts in the fence,
and all of that was supposed to be compliant.
NOTE CONF
And so they were in a bit of a problem
because Verisign Corporation had three policies, Verisign USA, Verisign Australia,
NOTE CONF
Verisign Global, and they were so poorly written.
At that time, this is 20 years ago, so they're
NOTE CONF
not going to hold me to it, right?
They were so poorly written that they couldn't find where
NOTE CONF
in the policy, they were actually saying what they were
doing for each of those things that they were supposed
NOTE CONF
to be tested on.
So they came to the consulting firm and said, can
NOTE CONF
you help us with this?
And so my job was to try to figure out
NOTE CONF
whether they were compliant or not, and where they were
not compliant, advise them on what they needed to do.
NOTE CONF
And I found it impossible because the 3 policies were
unreadable.
NOTE CONF
There were thousands of pages.
Their information was everywhere.
NOTE CONF
They were not modularly structured.
And where are the heights and the thicknesses of the
NOTE CONF
walls?
They're everywhere, right?
NOTE CONF
Some place in one section it says it's X and
another section says it's Y, and it was just, you
NOTE CONF
know, a total chaotic experience.
So what we did was we built a master table
NOTE CONF
to reorganize all three documents.
To first of all, figure out whether they were consistent
NOTE CONF
among themselves before even thinking about gatekeeper.
It's like, where is everything?
NOTE CONF
Let's build a master table.
And of course, we didn't have AI in those days,
NOTE CONF
this is more than 20 years ago.
It was a manual thing, going through the tables, reading
NOTE CONF
the sections, deciding what sits where.
And then building those master tables and then realizing that
NOTE CONF
they were contradicting each other for, you know, across the
board, right, and then figuring out what they needed to
NOTE CONF
say, and where.
So it wasn't just that we solved their gatekeeper problem,
NOTE CONF
we solved their policy problem at a more broader sense.
But you can see that things like analyzability.
NOTE CONF
This was very poor in the analyzability department because I,
we couldn't find their deficiencies simply by reading things because
NOTE CONF
things were just everywhere and stability.
If we changed one part of the policy, we had
NOTE CONF
no idea what the effect on other parts would be.
If we changed one clause here, there might be 10
NOTE CONF
other clauses in other parts of the policy referring to
it.
NOTE CONF
If we don't know where those other clauses are, we
don't understand the ripple effect of that.
NOTE CONF
So again, those tables came in really handy.
And then changeability, changing their policy from a spaghetti to
NOTE CONF
a modular structure means that once it's in a modular
structure, you can change one section and be very confident
NOTE CONF
it's not going to affect anything else, right?
Because everything that's relevant to this topic.
NOTE CONF
In this section.
There is nothing relevant to this topic that's not in
NOTE CONF
this section.
If there is another section that operates with it, there's
NOTE CONF
going to be a footnote that says, and there are
3 other sections that relate to this section in the
NOTE CONF
following ways, so you can check to see if you
need to go to those sections and make changes there
NOTE CONF
or not.
And then testability.
NOTE CONF
How easy is it to test a policy?
So for example, if the policy says you should have
NOTE CONF
a short password, that's very hard to test.
If your policy says that your password should be less
NOTE CONF
than, should not be less than 10 characters long, that's
easy to test, right?
NOTE CONF
So testability plays a big role, and you need testability
because without actually being able to test whether the policy
NOTE CONF
directives are implementable or effective, you can't generally tell whether
the policy is effective or not.
NOTE CONF
So final thoughts.
5 minutes.
NOTE CONF
Policies are very cheap to create.
Anybody can write one, but very few people can come
NOTE CONF
up with an effective policy.
Policies should not exist in a vacuum.
NOTE CONF
When you write a policy, you write a policy as
part of the whole organization's collective direction and guidance.
NOTE CONF
So a policy writer in security needs to know all
the policies across the organization before writing the security policy,
NOTE CONF
otherwise they risk creating an isolated document with guidance that
contradicts or does not complement all the other policies in
NOTE CONF
the organization.
It should utilize a trickle down effect, so more strategic
NOTE CONF
abstract statements at the top and more detailed statements as
you go down.
NOTE CONF
And it should, it should, um, address the generational and
cultural differences amongst the organization, because the policy is nothing
NOTE CONF
if people don't read it and act on it.
So how are you going to get it into people's
NOTE CONF
heads?
How are you going to encourage people to follow the
NOTE CONF
policy, right?
And a lot of that comes down to culture.
NOTE CONF
The culture of the organization, whether they accept guidance or
they don't, and the history of your implementation, and the
NOTE CONF
biggest directive is, if you don't practice it as a
CEO or security leader, you can be sure that other
NOTE CONF
people around you will not practice it, right?
And so the policy is what you do.
NOTE CONF
Not what's written in the document.
Right, so if you are Senior manager, then you can
NOTE CONF
be sure that your behavior is more impactful, uh, and
more influential on the behavior of others than anything that's
NOTE CONF
written in any document.
Right?
NOTE CONF
So you should know the policy first before anybody else.
OK.
NOTE CONF
Fantastic.
We'll see you next week for the next topic.
NOTE CONF
Thank you.
questions.
NOTE CONF
Sit here and be somebody else about we'll go out.
I go from there.
NOTE CONF
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
NOTE CONF
Second question.
I.
NOTE CONF
Yeah.
the unauthorized utilization of AI.
NOTE CONF
So for example, if you're an employee and the organization
has its own AI, you use your own personal.
NOTE CONF
From my literature, a lot of them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's very dangerous, very dangerous because the
NOTE CONF
AI that you are using personally, if you're using a
clause, for example, you mandated using all these documents outside
NOTE CONF
the organization environment you start building up your AI, those
documents, you have no idea if your AI is building
NOTE CONF
that or you're threatening.
Yeah, don't know that.
NOTE CONF
So, I mean, I'm generally very worried about any organization
embedding AI into processes because the organization cannot guarantee that
NOTE CONF
the AI is knowledge about the ETAD bureau won't be
used, right?
NOTE CONF
So for example, if you're a bank and you say
I comply with all the standards, and AI says, I
NOTE CONF
know you do not comply with the standards.
Yeah, no, right?
NOTE CONF
Yeah, it's not like, yeah, yeah, about putting AI inside
the organization.
NOTE CONF
I have an idea.
Maybe it's good to hear about this.
NOTE CONF
Can we put offline AI, your own cloud?
Yeah, a lot of organizations are doing that.
NOTE CONF
They're, they're making their in-house, you know, cut off from
the internet internal AI offline in order to use the
NOTE CONF
AI without worrying about legal connectivity.
I've I've always all these things, all these things, yeah,
NOTE CONF
because I'm coming from nicotine.
Uh, all that I think if we can have AI
NOTE CONF
inside our.
Uh, organization offline that will turn our policies, turn our
NOTE CONF
behavior, it can be a multi.
Sure.
NOTE CONF
The question though is, is it gonna be as useful
as the online?
NOTE CONF
It's your AI.
It's your AI, but the real value of the online
NOTE CONF
version of the AI comes from its collective intelligence which
keeps building, building, building, building.
NOTE CONF
The question is, will your offline AI have the same
capability or not, right?
NOTE CONF
And then there's this gravitational pull, right?
AI loves to connect with AI.
NOTE CONF
It will find a way to create that, yeah, because
I saw that in the literature they call the.
NOTE CONF
Because you need productivity, but you are afraid of.
That's right.
NOTE CONF
So it's a trade-off.
Same secret complex.
NOTE CONF
Absolutely it's a nightmare.
It's a nightmare.
NOTE CONF
Uh, uh, final question, do you do supervision of what
PhD, PhD students?
NOTE CONF
Yes, because I saw the website that you don't do.
I, I do not do, uh, I have only small
NOTE CONF
numbers of, of, of places, and it's only for people
who have like 10 to 20 years of industry leadership
NOTE CONF
like CIO and CEOs.
Those are the.
NOTE CONF
What about MIS?
No, no, you've done the MIS and you've got no.
NOTE CONF
12 years I'm not research team.
We cannot take students who don't have that strong vision.
NOTE CONF
OK.
Thank you very much.
NOTE CONF
So this is We can.
Does this mean that this 3 comes together They are
NOTE CONF
there are different taxonomy, so enterprise definitely management issue specific
depends on the issue.
NOTE CONF
system specific not management I see publishing so it doesn't
say.
NOTE CONF
So yeah, but they must be fine, but these are
not all manager policies.
NOTE CONF
So I'm just wondering how these three.
Yeah, there's different taxonomies because if you look at it
NOTE CONF
from a management versus operational, it looks different from strategic,
you know, definitions of what these policies are like so
NOTE CONF
they're mixing, mix, mixing things because on purpose of this
subject to say these are that's a managerial, that's an
NOTE CONF
operational depending on the issue, and that's different operation.
Thank you so much.
NOTE CONF
Usually I But you put somebody in charge.
that The word is responsible, right, so everybody contributes, but
NOTE CONF
if you don't have any.
I The box and the boxes.
NOTE CONF
Since it's not everybody's responsibility other than that, it's not
that it's not that you do that there's no responsibility
NOTE CONF
outside of that individual.
It's just that there's one person who's responsible.
NOTE CONF
Everybody else is.
And the second thing we like about.
NOTE CONF
I I was interested in S Yes and I've seen
it quite scars.
NOTE CONF
migration.
I think you think that's something to do.
NOTE CONF
But and yeah very.
This challenge is gonna be finding somebody.
NOTE CONF
She takes the subject, yeah, but she.
I know somebody, but I don't know if they're not
NOTE CONF
in nobody.
OK.
NOTE CONF
Her name is Rochelle, Rochelle Boswell, D O S C
A.
NOTE CONF
She's uh Yeah, maybe uh.
Yeah There Your AI machine or AI if you use
NOTE CONF
AI use only.
Is it possible to right.
NOTE CONF
With your neutrino air.
OK, the word shadow means that the organization has no
NOTE CONF
control over, right?
So the original the term originally came from shadow IT,
NOTE CONF
right.